<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Roller coaster of code</title><description>Roller coaster of code</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.7</generator><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 08:30:00 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>The lottery</title><description>&lt;p&gt;When purchasing a lottery ticket there is around one chance in 14 millions of winning the jackpot. Even though I know that those odds are next to impossible, occasionally I pick numbers and do participate. There are two reasons to explain my irrational behaviour, firstly as slim are my chances&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/the-lottery/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">ecde3f1c-3039-4e3f-95ce-75b36e7d70ce</guid><dc:creator>Jonathan Passe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 08:28:07 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;When purchasing a lottery ticket there is around one chance in 14 millions of winning the jackpot. Even though I know that those odds are next to impossible, occasionally I pick numbers and do participate. There are two reasons to explain my irrational behaviour, firstly as slim are my chances of winning they still do exist. Secondly as long as I have not seen the lottery results, I get to be a potential Millionaire. As such I picture what my life should be like, it often follows the following: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1- Buy assets that will secure my newly acquired fortune. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2- Take care of my loved ones (not as in putting a contract over their head, but help them achieve their goals)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3- Go travel around the world and have  fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4-... And I guess doing something meaningful with my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's right, even in my multi-millionaire fantasy I see myself working! I will not try to discuss  here the reasons why, as it would probably require years of psychoanalysis but I will point out what element I would want in a job, when money is not a necessity. &lt;br&gt;  
My ideal job would need to be interesting, intellectually challenging, fun and have an element of flexibility ( in the fantasy I am travelling around the world remember?). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like many people that decided to change their career I realised that I could not find those elements in the job I had, so if what I was doing was not fun to me, or stimulating and I was not earning, a "winning the lottery" level salary, why would I keep doing that and what shall I do instead? I did a list of what was fun and stimulating to me in my current job and I realised that a lot of it involved, creating things, trying to implement ideas, data analysis and playing around with excel. I also remembered how much I enjoyed taking algorithm classes in university a few years back. After a bit of research I started to realise that Web development may be the answer. A field that offered a lot of jobs, something that seemed fun, creative, challenging and that could allow me to work virtually anywhere in the world, for any type of company. And even though it might not make a multi-millionaire out of me ( but who cares, I can still play the lottery) , something offering a very competitive salary. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
The question then was, How could I become a developer?...&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>What does happen after we die?</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I won't pretend that I have an answer to that, however if it was up to me, we would get the opportunity to watch a film of our lives. &lt;br&gt;
Seeing ourselves learning to take a first step, then a second one, and another one, to fall, to stand up again,&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/what-does-happen-after-we-die/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">1da36953-6efe-4067-ad8e-42666c52dd01</guid><dc:creator>Jonathan Passe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 08:27:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I won't pretend that I have an answer to that, however if it was up to me, we would get the opportunity to watch a film of our lives. &lt;br&gt;
Seeing ourselves learning to take a first step, then a second one, and another one, to fall, to stand up again, take another step... &lt;br&gt;
Actually thinking about it, that movie would be long (I hope, very long and happy in my case) and probably very boring, I mean it already took me ages to describe myself learning how to walk. &lt;br&gt;
But I guess that being the afterlife and all, Ingmar Bergman, or Federico Fellini could edit the movie of my life, to only show the interesting parts. &lt;br&gt;
I like this idea but in case it doesn't happen, I will use this platform to tell the tale of my journey on the path to become a developer, which hopefully will bear some interest ( and maybe one will be adapted into a movie... you know in the afterlife)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>It's alive !</title><description>&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QuoKNZjr8_U" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/its-alive/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">1e05072c-186a-43e4-8a33-5208d9a63519</guid><dc:creator>Jonathan Passe</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 13:25:05 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QuoKNZjr8_U" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>