<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0"><channel><title>Roller coaster of code</title><description>Roller coaster of code</description><link>http://localhost:2368/</link><generator>Ghost 0.7</generator><lastBuildDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 16:20:58 GMT</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://localhost:2368/rss/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><ttl>60</ttl><item><title>Smart Tabs #2</title><description>&lt;p&gt;In case you missed my previous Smart Tabs &lt;a href="https://jojograndjojo.github.io/smart-tabs-2/"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; I am trying to build an app, which would sort of be Guitar Hero meets Shazam, or rather I happen to know Guitar Hero and Shazam and decide to organise a blind date for them( blind because I will use technology&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/smart-tabs-2-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">5cebe0fb-fce7-43e1-9009-f9771cd79997</guid><dc:creator>Jonathan Passe</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2016 16:20:48 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In case you missed my previous Smart Tabs &lt;a href="https://jojograndjojo.github.io/smart-tabs-2/"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt; I am trying to build an app, which would sort of be Guitar Hero meets Shazam, or rather I happen to know Guitar Hero and Shazam and decide to organise a blind date for them( blind because I will use technology that is new to me...I might need to refactor that analogy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This project is the first one that I am going to work on by myself. Still I intend to apply the principles I learnt so far, test driven development, refactoring, retrospectives (I will do stand up by myself but whilst walking and talking in my head, so nobody thinks I am crazy).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First of all to stick to &lt;a href="http://www.agilemanifesto.org/principles.html"&gt;agile principles&lt;/a&gt; I had to translate the functionalities of my application into user stories (you can have a look at them &lt;a href="https://github.com/Jojograndjojo/smart_tabs"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;), those functionalities being:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes are being displayed as they are being played.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;There is a list of songs to play, when chosen they display a tablature (or something similar).  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Notes are changing visually when they are being played to check.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The tablature should show the part the player is about to play.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Coding, involves being stuck from time to time,  and often when stuck on a particular issue,  loosing sight of what the structure of should be like can happen. An easy way to exit the "What the hell am I doing again?" zone is to diagram what you are trying to achieve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The following is the domain model that I originally designed, polygons representing a classes and arrow representing messages between sent to those classes &lt;br&gt;
&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/08/WP_20160809_19_15_20_Pro.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although domain modelling is convenient, it is also important to remember that ( if you happen not to be perfect, like me) you might be subject to make some errors when creating it and therefore not to follow it religiously all the way through the project. &lt;br&gt;
In this instance for example I would be in trouble as I forgot to include an object to handle the output. Oops....&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Smart Tabs #1</title><description>&lt;p&gt;During my time at &lt;a href="http://www.makersacademy.com/"&gt;Makers Academy&lt;/a&gt;, I did participate in several projects and learnt a lot that way. &lt;br&gt;
Once the studying at Makers would be done, I thought that  I should keep doing projects and use them as a vector to keep my learning going. &lt;br&gt;
The project seemed secondary but&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/smart-tabs-2/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">9e4958d4-bc82-4c1d-a4da-c87ba6893504</guid><dc:creator>Jonathan Passe</dc:creator><pubDate>Wed, 31 Aug 2016 11:32:54 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;During my time at &lt;a href="http://www.makersacademy.com/"&gt;Makers Academy&lt;/a&gt;, I did participate in several projects and learnt a lot that way. &lt;br&gt;
Once the studying at Makers would be done, I thought that  I should keep doing projects and use them as a vector to keep my learning going. &lt;br&gt;
The project seemed secondary but then something happen.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If you happen to walk through Spitafields market in  London on a Friday, you might see this man playing the piano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="http://localhost:2368/content/images/2016/08/spitafields_pianist.jpg" alt=""&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Like I did, you might notice the tablet the pianist is reading music from. &lt;br&gt;
And like I did you may think "Wouldn't it be cool if the 'pages' were 'turning' as the music is playing, so the player could keep his fingers on the keys..." &lt;br&gt;
And like I did, you may also think "What if it tracked your progress, like guitar hero but for people who can actually play music" &lt;br&gt;
And like I did, you may also think "What about a composer mode ?" &lt;br&gt;
Well if you did actually think all of that, you have no personality, it's my idea get your own. &lt;br&gt;
Anyway it does seem like a technically challenging task to build an application that would do all of that, but still I will give it a shot&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Job Hit List</title><description>&lt;p&gt;To get something I have to really want it, that's how it always seems to work for me and I guess it is fair. I want to get a developer  job and thanks Tim Berners-Lee, there are plenty of jobs around. However I do not want any job, I need&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/job-hit-list/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">6b5cd2c2-bce7-44bd-a780-b03d9263bf99</guid><dc:creator>Jonathan Passe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2016 17:29:12 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;To get something I have to really want it, that's how it always seems to work for me and I guess it is fair. I want to get a developer  job and thanks Tim Berners-Lee, there are plenty of jobs around. However I do not want any job, I need to find the one(s) that I will really really want and if  I don't I will stay jobless... Again I do not get things that I do not really really want. &lt;br&gt;
But what would this(those) special(s) job(s) be?....&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I decided to list and filter companies that hired junior developers by using an excel sheet, which I didn't find very user friendly. &lt;br&gt;
And then it hit me... &lt;br&gt;
I can code! Why don't I build an app that would match my requirements. &lt;br&gt;
Behold "Job hit list":&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe src="https://player.vimeo.com/video/180764029" width="640" height="373" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen="" mozallowfullscreen="" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;  

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/180764029"&gt;job-hit-list-mvp&lt;/a&gt; from &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com/user56070124"&gt;Jonathan Passe&lt;/a&gt; on &lt;a href="https://vimeo.com"&gt;Vimeo&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The idea is to keep a record and relevant information about cool companies and have the option of doing it collaboratively. &lt;br&gt;
I happen to know quite a few people that are looking for a dev job as well, but the type of jobs they want may differ from the type of jobs I want. Lets say I meet a person at a tech event, and they are looking for developers, it seems like a good company and an interesting job but still it does not feel like it would be for me. &lt;br&gt;
Well I can still add the details about the company and share the information with fellow coders (and they will owe me for life :-) ). &lt;br&gt;
The app is in its minimum viable product stage, I still need to add filters and make it look nicer, but I can (and do ) use it...&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Feel free to review my &lt;a href="https://github.com/Jojograndjojo/hit_list"&gt;code&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Makers Academy Graduate</title><description>&lt;p&gt;So I just graduated from MA. This is the point where I am meant to find a job. The course and living in London for 3 months with no income is obviously expensive. It would be tempting to jump at the first opportunity that presents itself right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well yes, but&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/domain-modelling/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">32cf0761-0794-4b59-8742-db52492514f8</guid><dc:creator>Jonathan Passe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 16:17:28 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;So I just graduated from MA. This is the point where I am meant to find a job. The course and living in London for 3 months with no income is obviously expensive. It would be tempting to jump at the first opportunity that presents itself right?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Well yes, but that will not be the course of action I decided to take, the truth is right now, I have very little idea about what kind of jobs are out there, even though there seem to be a lot of jobs available.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What I am planning to do over the next few weeks is meet as many professional as I can, not in the hope of finding a job (although if something cool presents itself, why not...), but to find out how different professionals are actually working what are they working on and see if it would something I would see myself doing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I happened to go to the an agile Meetup in about an hour, which should be interesting as it is the way I would like to be working, I need to remember to ask the following questions :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What kind of work do you do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What does a week of work looks like?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;How many people are in your team?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you use TDD ?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you have retros?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do you use pair programming?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What kind of tasks your juniors do?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I actually need to leave now if I don't want to be late, I shall edit that post in the future and update the questions if needed...&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>Fast forward &gt;&gt;</title><description>&lt;p&gt;In case you did not notice I am using ghost as a platform for this blog. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Why ghost?" You might want to ask, well because of that :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-ruby"&gt;def write_code  
  "I can write code snippets :)"
end  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And because when I started to walk the web dev path, it was recommended&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/learn-to-code-in-12-weeks/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">20167c56-ab22-4229-974f-08e369f1fe26</guid><dc:creator>Jonathan Passe</dc:creator><pubDate>Thu, 18 Aug 2016 15:46:27 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;In case you did not notice I am using ghost as a platform for this blog. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;"Why ghost?" You might want to ask, well because of that :&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class="language-ruby"&gt;def write_code  
  "I can write code snippets :)"
end  
&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And because when I started to walk the web dev path, it was recommended to me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing I didn't know back then was that, to host a ghost blog free on github, I had to use &lt;code&gt;Node&lt;/code&gt;. And back then I didn't really know what &lt;code&gt;Node.js&lt;/code&gt; was , or &lt;code&gt;git&lt;/code&gt; or most importantly a stack trace. &lt;br&gt;
I just thought the command line hated me, when it was just telling me what I needed to do (communication is key in a command line/dev relationship)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Anyway I came a long way in about 3 months. "How?" You may want to ask. I joined the &lt;a href="http://www.makersacademy.com/"&gt;Makers Academy&lt;/a&gt;, Europe's leading Web Developer bootcamp (as their website say(it is sometimes hard to pass the right tone when writing, just to be clear, going there was a great idea for me( putting parentheses within parentheses is bad practice)). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Where I went from "Ouais!! I can get my laptop to tell me my own age!" (I happen to be French, Ouais !! means yeah!!). To be able to write applications like the following:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=a4NPua1kmD0"&gt;Time for an Adventure&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Working in groups, using &lt;a href="http://agiledata.org/essays/tdd.html#WhatIsTDD"&gt;test driven development&lt;/a&gt; , trying to follow &lt;a href="http://agilemethodology.org/"&gt;agile&lt;/a&gt; and stick to the &lt;a href="http://www.extremeprogramming.org/values.html"&gt;xp values&lt;/a&gt;. I will get to talk more about all of this in future posts. &lt;br&gt;
But right now all I am trying to say is sorry to my numerous readers (Haha...), I stopped to publish posts as I was busy getting the skills allowing to... well publish posts but also getting  to become a better developer. I hope you will find the strength to forgive me.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ps : If you are struggling setting up a ghost blog yourself have a look at the following &lt;a href="http://blog.sunnyg.io/2015/09/24/ghost-with-github/"&gt;post&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>The lottery</title><description>&lt;p&gt;When purchasing a lottery ticket there is around one chance in 14 millions of winning the jackpot. Even though I know that those odds are next to impossible, occasionally I pick numbers and do participate. There are two reasons to explain my irrational behaviour, firstly as slim are my chances&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/the-lottery/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">ecde3f1c-3039-4e3f-95ce-75b36e7d70ce</guid><dc:creator>Jonathan Passe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 08:28:07 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;When purchasing a lottery ticket there is around one chance in 14 millions of winning the jackpot. Even though I know that those odds are next to impossible, occasionally I pick numbers and do participate. There are two reasons to explain my irrational behaviour, firstly as slim are my chances of winning they still do exist. Secondly as long as I have not seen the lottery results, I get to be a potential Millionaire. As such I picture what my life should be like, it often follows the following: &lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;1- Buy assets that will secure my newly acquired fortune. &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;2- Take care of my loved ones (not as in putting a contract over their head, but help them achieve their goals)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;3- Go travel around the world and have  fun.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;4-... And I guess doing something meaningful with my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That's right, even in my multi-millionaire fantasy I see myself working! I will not try to discuss  here the reasons why, as it would probably require years of psychoanalysis but I will point out what element I would want in a job, when money is not a necessity. &lt;br&gt;  
My ideal job would need to be interesting, intellectually challenging, fun and have an element of flexibility ( in the fantasy I am travelling around the world remember?). &lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;p&gt;Like many people that decided to change their career I realised that I could not find those elements in the job I had, so if what I was doing was not fun to me, or stimulating and I was not earning, a "winning the lottery" level salary, why would I keep doing that and what shall I do instead? I did a list of what was fun and stimulating to me in my current job and I realised that a lot of it involved, creating things, trying to implement ideas, data analysis and playing around with excel. I also remembered how much I enjoyed taking algorithm classes in university a few years back. After a bit of research I started to realise that Web development may be the answer. A field that offered a lot of jobs, something that seemed fun, creative, challenging and that could allow me to work virtually anywhere in the world, for any type of company. And even though it might not make a multi-millionaire out of me ( but who cares, I can still play the lottery) , something offering a very competitive salary. &lt;br&gt; &lt;br&gt;
The question then was, How could I become a developer?...&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>What does happen after we die?</title><description>&lt;p&gt;I won't pretend that I have an answer to that, however if it was up to me, we would get the opportunity to watch a film of our lives. &lt;br&gt;
Seeing ourselves learning to take a first step, then a second one, and another one, to fall, to stand up again,&lt;/p&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/what-does-happen-after-we-die/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">1da36953-6efe-4067-ad8e-42666c52dd01</guid><dc:creator>Jonathan Passe</dc:creator><pubDate>Tue, 14 Jun 2016 08:27:03 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;p&gt;I won't pretend that I have an answer to that, however if it was up to me, we would get the opportunity to watch a film of our lives. &lt;br&gt;
Seeing ourselves learning to take a first step, then a second one, and another one, to fall, to stand up again, take another step... &lt;br&gt;
Actually thinking about it, that movie would be long (I hope, very long and happy in my case) and probably very boring, I mean it already took me ages to describe myself learning how to walk. &lt;br&gt;
But I guess that being the afterlife and all, Ingmar Bergman, or Federico Fellini could edit the movie of my life, to only show the interesting parts. &lt;br&gt;
I like this idea but in case it doesn't happen, I will use this platform to tell the tale of my journey on the path to become a developer, which hopefully will bear some interest ( and maybe one will be adapted into a movie... you know in the afterlife)&lt;/p&gt;</content:encoded></item><item><title>It's alive !</title><description>&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QuoKNZjr8_U" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description><link>http://localhost:2368/its-alive/</link><guid isPermaLink="false">1e05072c-186a-43e4-8a33-5208d9a63519</guid><dc:creator>Jonathan Passe</dc:creator><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jun 2016 13:25:05 GMT</pubDate><content:encoded>&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/QuoKNZjr8_U" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</content:encoded></item></channel></rss>